Profile:

A dynamic Digital Transformation leader guiding organizations around the world to continuously improve their software delivery performance in order to improve their time to market, customer responsiveness, market share and financial results. I offer a deep background of Leadership, Lean, ITSM, Compliance, Cloud, DevOps, Software Delivery and Product Management helping organizations tackle modern software challenges around delayed time to market, developer productivity and context shifting, DevOps handoffs and dependencies and high volumes of DevOps toil. When you work with me you will experience the benefit of a lifelong learner forever innovating who brings an attitude of learning, evolving and growing to the organizations he leads and guides.

Work Experience:

DevOps Consultant

2/2017 - Present Sumplify, Denver, CO

Guiding organization through their DevOps transformations and improving their software delivery performance by focusing on the 4 DevOps cornerstones: Technical Practices, Automation, Architecture and Culture.

- Delivered a DevOps Assessment and VSM service to an Application Services Software Company guiding their Digital Transportation journey and increasing their relevance with customers advancing their network automation solutions
- Delivered a DevOps Transformation Blueprint to an international Software Development and Delivery leader, implementing an automated self-service software delivery tool, helping them eliminate hours of DevOps toil helping them delay forecasted cost of hiring an additional DevOps Engineer
- Delivered a Value Stream Mapping Service (VSM) and a subsequent self-service portal to a Global Financial Services
 client ultimately empowering them to reduce their time to market by 4 weeks and double their productivity
- Delivered a DevOps Culture and Relationship Mapping Assessment to a Marketing Automation client which helped evolve their DevOps culture and reduce handoffs and dependencies across their Software Delivery Lifecycle

Director, Application Delivery

11/2013 – 1/2017 Seguoia Worldwide, Campbell, CA (Acquired by Presidio Networks)

Led team of DevOps engineers responsible for infrastructure/productivity automation, environment provisioning, build health / branch management, deployment health, environment management, SOP'S, knowledge transfer and support transition. Additional role serving as Product Manager for separate Cloud Commerce Platform software product.

- Having lost key personnel, employed transformational leadership in order to retain, stabilize and grow team in chaotic environment characterized by conflict, hardship and a culture of local goals (e.g. velocity, utilization)
- Stabilized the software delivery lifecycle with delivery / deployment standardization, CICD automation, (e.g. Jenkins, Puppet, Selenium, AWS, etc) and by streamlining our hotfix delivery process
- Achieved increased deployment frequency (monthly to weekly), shorter lead time for changes (months to weeks), shorter MTTR (days to hours) and lower change fail rate (>50% to <25%)
- Member of leadership team achieving successful acquisition outcome
- Key inventor on a patent for innovative new Cloud Commerce Platform Ecosystem Framework (patent pending)

Cloud Business Strategist

4/2011 - 11/2013 Cisco Systems, San Jose, CA

Deliver a broad range of strategic business initiatives from strategic customer projects to innovative partner ventures to driving a global cloud sales and delivery enablement program.

- Drove numerous software-centric strategic projects for some of Cisco's top customers and business partners (e.g. Thomson Reuters and Ingram Micro) resulting in \$2M+ in bookings
- Co-architected and wrote a business case for an industry first cloud service aggregator model for a strategic Cisco distributor looking to monetize their extensive ISV and channel partner relationships
- Established a global cloud automation software field enablement program for 150+ sales and delivery resources (Cisco and partners). Program:

- achieved strategically significant cloud automation and management high ground in key Cisco accounts
- grew net new software and services revenue by 200%+
- Leveraging the TOGAF Enterprise Architecture framework, developed and successfully piloted a comprehensive ITaaS service offering based on Cisco IT's "Cisco on Cisco" IT Transformation story

Director, Strategic Services

6/2007 – 4/2011 newScale, Inc., San Mateo, CA (Acquired by Cisco Systems)

Built a Strategic Consulting practice which served as a critical driver for newScale business, partner and practice development as well as product management, marketing and customer solution delivery. Member of leadership team that successfully transformed the organization from an enterprise service catalog focus to an enterprise cloud focus.

- Built comprehensive service portfolio which encompassed service catalog pre-launch, launch, expand and adoption services, added over 20 new customers in result; ultimately receiving Sales Performance Award
- Led a critical customer success program targeting crucial adoption services for stuck or at risk clients, ultimately retaining 6 strategic customers; 3 of which joined the 1 Million service requisitions club and 1 whose program and CIO were showcased by The Wall Street Journal
- Central to newScale's cloud focused transformation, built cloud maturity model and cloud maturity assessment (based on extensive market research and benchmarking) which helped numerous organizations set and validate their cloud computing strategy
- Transformed implementation methodology accounting for full breadth of cloud people, process and technology requirements enabling significant improvements in speed and agility - enabled strategic retail customer to reduce cycle time for delivering a test server environment from 12 weeks to 30 minutes
- Transformation success achieved when newScale was awarded the Best of VMworld 2010 Award for Private Cloud Solutions and was subsequently acquired by Cisco as a core component in their cloud software suite

ITSM Practice Leader

12/2002 – 6/2007 Pepperweed Consulting, Pittsburgh, PA

Founded a \$6M consulting business managing practice development, sales, marketing and solution delivery. Offered best in industry consulting services for the implementation of ITIL best practices.

- Accounted for > \$6M in annual revenue by leading presales, delivery and account management for numerous strategic accounts.
- Recruited, trained and professionally developed 20 of the top ITSM consultants in the industry
- Managed the creation of a comprehensive set of pre-sales and delivery packages and consulting materials
- Achieved 90% + consultant utilization rate while adding over 30 new customers to the company account ranks

Service Level Manager

9/1999 - 11/2001 Level 3 Communications, Broomfield, CO

Managed customer relationship between IT and IT's business stakeholders. Baselined and continually improved business aligned IT service quality through a constant cycle of negotiating, measuring, reporting and reviewing IT service achievements and consequently initiating corrective actions to eradicate unacceptable levels of service.

- Architected an industry first business process aligned Service Level Management program. Negotiated 36 process aligned global SLA's, which covered 297 applications in 3 regions with only a 2 person team.
- Reengineered the Incident Management process. Reduced MTTR targets by 27% through process improvements and Remedy system enhancements while concurrently experiencing a 33% reduction in IT support staff.
- Institutionalized a comprehensive post mortem incident review process which identified and tracked outage issues through resolution.

Lean Six Sigma Black Belt

6/1998 - 9/1999 GE Capital AFS, Barrington, IL

Responsible for forming and leading cross functional business process reengineering teams; applying GE's metric driven change management methodologies.

- Co-managed accounting center consolidation, reducing headcount from 86 to 42. Outsourced 20 % of accounting center in parallel with office consolidation.
- Served as a member of the GE Corporate Audit Staff auditing accounting process controls and quality.
- Built customer focused process management system resulting in better fiscal close and cash control processes.

Education and Certifications:

University of Colorado, Boulder BA - Economics

DevOps: DevOps Foundation and DevOps Leader Certifications (DevOps Institute)

Lean: GE Six Sigma Quality Black Belt Certification

Cloud: Amazon Web Services (AWS) Business Professional and Technical Professional Accreditations

Compliance: Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA) (not current)

ITSM: IT Infrastructure Library (ITIL) Manager's Certificate in IT Service Management (ITSM)

Patent:

Hybrid Cloud Ecosystem Consumption Model - Filed Aug 11, 2015 - us 62203786

A method of engaging Ecosystem stakeholders in an emerging hybrid Cloud marketplace model. A comprehensive hybrid cloud commerce model or cloud commerce platform (CCP) bringing Ecosystem stakeholders (Service Providers, VARs "Value Added Resellers, System Integrators, Solution Providers, and Customers/End Users) together for consumption based transactions. A method of moving away from Capital Expenditures, towards Operational Expenditures based on Hybrid Cloud technologies involving, but not limited to: SaaS, PaaS, laaS and other consumption based models.